

Siddhant Kushwaha

11 k16.siddhant@gmail.com

+91 73516 51000

Ashok Vihar, Haldwani Uttarakhand, India

Profile

Versatile skill set with experience in Data Engineering, Information Retrieval, Android App Development, and Web Development. Knowledgeable in Algorithms and Data Structures. Adept at implementing apps and program modules in C++, Python, Java, Kotlin and JavaScript.

Work Experience

Analyst Developer (Remote Intern), Egregore Labs — August 2019 - Present I work on problems around Information Retrieval, and Data Engineering. Some of my work includes Table Understanding, Form understanding from images, Distributed Computing, and Web Crawling.

Analyst Developer (Full time Intern), Egregore Labs — May 2019 - July 2019 Worked on building solutions for Information Retrieval, Data Structuring, and Data Processing. Also worked on the project for Web Regression Testing Automation.

Android App Developer, Cheruvu — May 2018 - Present

Former Android App Developer intern at Cheruvu, a startup for farmers. Led the app development team and also worked on backend based on Spring and MongoDb. Currently on contract as a Freelance Consultant for the company.

Projects

Table Extraction

Extracting the tables present in images based on their grid. OCR was used for text. OpenCV was used for image processing.

Pothole Cop

An app that lets users report potholes to the Government based on severity of the issue which is decided via a Machine Learning Algorithm.

Lucy

Lucene based search engine for places, data was collected and structured to allow ranking the results based on query parameters like location, description etc.

Achievements

Runner up at Google India Hackathon, October 2018, Hyderabad

Qualified for ACM ICPC Regionals, 2017

Won second prize for Appathon at College TechFest.

Skills

Languages - C, C++, Python, Java, Kotlin, JavaScript

Tools/Frameworks - Android Studio, Ionic, Django, Flask, Scrapy, Selenium, TensorFlow, Keras, Spacy

Database - MySQL, MongoDb, Firebase

Others - Git, Bash, AWS EC2, AWS S3

Education

IIIT Sri City — B. Tech. Computer Science, 2016 - Present

Aryaman Vikram Birla Institute of Learning — XII, 2015 - 2016